It's cold!
Wow! Did you see that, Ioryogi-san?
Huh? See what?
Here it goes again.
There! Isn't that something?!
I guess it's winter...
Look! Look how big!
It really is the dead of winter, isn't it?
How was that? Heat you up a bit?
You're horrible.
Wow!
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...Warmth of the Wintry Wind.
Hey Kobato.
What is it, Ioryogi-san?
What comes after winter?
Spring.
Exactly. There isn't much time
before spring. You know that?
You have got to fill this bottle
with kompeito by spring.
Yes.
But if you don't hurry,
you are not going anywhere!
Yes.
So I woke up this morning and my Dad?
He was sleeping with his stomach uncovered.
You're kidding. Well let me tell
you what my brother...
What's the matter?
That man. He's here today, too.
Come along.
Honey, let's stay home today.
Mommy?
Hey. I'm going to call the police.
I haven't stepped one foot in.
You have nothing to complain about.
This is harassment.
I'm just standing here.
This kindergarten isn't really a safe
place to leave your kids, is it?
Fujimoto?
This guy...
It's that debt collector from the other day.
Let's go.
But...
Leave him.
Hello. Yomogi Kindergarten.
Oh, Rikako's Mom.
I was worried because Rikako didn't come today.
So... does that mean?
I understand. I'll be waiting
for the forms in the mail.
Yes. Yes. That will be fine.
Well then, please tell Rikako to stay well.
Rikako has quit kindergarten.
Huh?!
That's three...
...this month, already.
But the way things are I can't really
blame the parents for worrying.
Huh? Of course that won't do!
You deal with it yourself! Huh? Huh?!
Great! There's so much!
Thank you, Domoto.
No problem. It's just stuff lying around at
home or left over from the school festival.
It's a great help. We'll be able to
have a fun Christmas party.
Ms. Sayaka.
Yes?
Please don't work yourself too hard.
I'll be all right.
Um...
If you're looking for Fujimoto and Kobato,
they're up on the roof.
Thanks.
Ms. Sayaka seemed sad to let her go.
Of course she was the same,
kind Ms. Sayaka we know.
But she seemed very sad.
Yeah.
That man...
And that when the due date arrives,
I'm going to shut down the kindergarten.
You can't do that!
I don't care if children are attending.
Tell her if she doesn't want anyone
injured, to pack her things and go.
How can he be so mean?
Mr. Okiura is Ms. Sayaka's husband, isn't he?
He doesn't deserve being called that!
I'm...
I'm going to go and have a talk with that man!
Huh?
Don't go!
But he's being a disturbance, right?
He's not the type that will listen.
If I talk to him properly,
I'm sure he'll understand.
I'm telling you not to go down there!
Why not?!
Just listen to me. Don't you get involved!
But if another child quits,
Ms. Sayaka will be so sad!
That's not something you have to worry about!
I'm telling you, don't do anything!
But...
Domoto?
What's up?
Is something the matter?
That's three... this month already.
But the way things are I can't really
blame the parents for worrying.
I see...
We've got to do something.
If there was an easy solution,
Fujimoto would have found it long ago.
I understand how you feel Kobato,
but really, you shouldn't.
But I'm going to go and ask him.
But...
If we leave things alone, there will be
no more Yomogi Kindergarten.
That will make everyone sad.
So I'm going to go over and just talk to him.
Kobato!
Snow!
Let's fill the place with snow!
That would be pretty.
Can we make it all white with snow?
Teacher Kiyokazu!
Let's decorate this together!
Uh, sure...
There are round ones around it, so we'll
add small balls and surround it.
And then guess what?
What is Dobato up to now?
Who are you?
I'm Kobato Hanato!
Huh?
It's a nice day today.
If you hang your bedding out on days
like this it gets soft and warm.
Play lots outside and have a nice nap in the soft
futon and say let's do it all again tomorrow.
Because tomorrow, everybody will be back
at Yomogi Kindergarten again.
What on earth are you talking about?
We went on picnics too!
We even made pictures with fallen leaves!
Digging for sweet potatoes was fun! And lots of
people came to our bazaar the other day!
You know what? This kindergarten is filled
with everybody's thoughts and feelings.
It's full of it! So please!
Please don't close Yomogi Kindergarten down!
Please!
Pay back the money before you talk like that.
I understand that.
So we'll pay it back a little bit at a time!
Kobato. Talking to this man won't...
Is something wrong?!
It's none of your business.
This guy is right. Talking to me
will not get you anywhere.
Then I'll talk to Mr. Okiura.
He's not going to listen to someone like you.
Besides...
The kindergarten is the last place his
old man is going to take pity on.
His father?
Well I'm leaving now, but I tell you, I'll be back.
Please! Save Yomogi Kindergarten!
See you!
Kobato, let's just forget it for today.
Okay.
Are you all right?!
Is your stomach hurting you?!
Get away from me!
But...
Shut up! Just leave me alone!
I cannot leave you alone!
Are you going to be okay?
What's wrong?! Are you all right?!
Hey, it's Kobato.
Domoto's there too!
He suddenly collapsed!
Kobato went with them.
Yeah...
Ms. Sayaka!
Hm?
The ambulance.
It went away sounding its siren, didn't it?
Yes it did.
Now.
You get some sleep.
Good afternoon, Yomogi Kindergarten.
Appendicitis?
Uh-huh.
Okay. I'll tell Ms. Sayaka too.
Kobato.
The operation was successful.
They say he's going to be okay now.
Really?
Really. No worries.
Oh good.
Shall we go then?
Yes.
Oh?
I wonder what you're calling about.
That guy you put in front of the kindergarten...
He had appendicitis and collapsed.
Appendicitis?
He's at Central Hospital.
The operation apparently went well.
Is that right? Well, sorry for the trouble.
Yeah. You're big trouble.
Well then get off of that land.
You have no way of paying me back.
You understand?
Is there any room for negotiation?
Negotiation?
What is so amusing?!
What's with you? This isn't like you at all.
Huh?! I'm asking you if it's possible!
I'd say it's not. Thanks for
letting me know, anyway.
Oh, and uh...
What is it?
Why don't you just give up and leave the
kindergarten, Fujimoto dear?
Why did I call him?
If I talk to him properly,
I'm sure he'll understand.
We're back.
Hey.
Um. The gentleman was okay.
They say he'll be fine soon.
Is that right.
Bye Kobato!
Yes. Bye-bye!
Mommy, you know what?
Rikako quit kindergarten.
Really? Is that so?
Kobato, you're free to go now.
But there's still tidying to do.
You've had a hard day.
Go home and get some rest.
We're going to get busy again with
Christmas decorating tomorrow. Okay?
Okay.
I'll walk you home.
Domoto.
Thanks for your help today.
Don't mention it.
I didn't really do anything.
I'll go get my bag.
Ioryogi-san, thank you for waiting.
Look at this. No kompeitos today.
What are you going to do about it?
But that man's going to be okay.
And that's good.
How could that be good?! You know what he's
going to do once he gets better! You...
What's wrong?
Fujimoto was angry with me.
He told me not to do anything and I...
You did nothing wrong, Kobato.
There's no reason to be concerned.
But...
Kobato?
What do you say we sit down for a bit?
What could be the best option?
If Yomogi Kindergarten gets shut down,
everyone is going to be so unhappy.
What is there that can I do?
Kobato...
You're always concerned about
the people around you.
You are kind and straightforward.
Kobato, you're always trying your best.
Kobato.
I like girls like you, Kobato.
Domoto.
Thank you very much!
Thank you. I feel a bit better now.
You're very welcome.
Here.
Oh...
It's nice and warm.
Thank you very much.
Kobato.
Yes? What is it?
On Christmas Day...
Would you like to...
Fujimoto.
Just getting home?
Yeah.
Oh. Let me know if you need anything
else for the Christmas party.
Yeah.
Thank you for the scarf.
Sure.
Well then, see you.
Goodbye.
See you.
Yeah.
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...White Christmas.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...White Christmas.